Frenemies unite.
The Angry Birds Movie 2 is a animation, adventure,
comedy film directed by Thurop Van Orman.
Red, Chuck, Bomb and the rest of their feathered friends are surprised when a green pig
suggests that they put aside their differences and unite to fight a common threat.
Aggressive birds from an island covered in ice are planning to use
an elaborate weapon to destroy the fowl and swine.
Red (voice), played by Jason Sudeikis.
Chuck (voice), played by Josh Gad.
Bomb (voice), played by Danny McBride.
Zeta (voice), played by Leslie Jones.
Leonard (voice), played by Bill Hader.
Silver (voice), played by Rachel Bloom.
The Angry Birds Movie 2 is a 2019 American animated comedy
film based on the Angry Birds video game series.
Directed by Thurop Van Orman and written by Peter
Ackerman, Eyal Podell and Jonathon E.
Stewart, the film stars Jason Sudeikis, Josh Gad, Bill Hader, Danny McBride, and Peter Dinklage reprising
their roles from the first film, with Leslie Jones, Rachel Bloom, Awkwafina, Sterling K.
Brown, and Eugenio Derbez joining the cast.
In the film, the birds are forced to team up with the pigs to stop Eagle
Island's leader from destroying both of their islands.
Heitor Pereira returned to compose the film's score, with artists such as
Kesha and Luke Combs contributing tracks for the film.
It also features classical pop songs from the
1960s to 2000s, as in the first film.
The Angry Birds Movie 2 was theatrically released in Finland on August 7, 2019, by SF
Studios, and in the United States on August 14, by Sony Pictures Releasing.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics and
grossed $153 million on a $65 million budget.
A sequel, The Angry Birds Movie 3, is due to be released on December 23, 2026.
The film explores themes of island, rivalry,
sequel, family, based on video game.
The tone is lighthearted.